Saïd Ziani

Having a track record of continually improving the way software works, I'm trying always to apply my technical know-how to build and improve large-scale, distributed, modern (not only) and high-volume systems. I like to understand complex architectures, to be involved in solving challenging technical problems and become expert on the components that I build or enhance.



saidziani.pro@gmail.com

+31 6 19988210

Amsterdam, Netherlands

github.com/saidziani

Work experience

11/2021 - present Utrecht, NL

Software Engineer - Data Acquisition

data.ai, formerly AppAnnie

- Analyze the technical feasibility of data collection product features and help guide development.
- Design and implement performant, scalable, and distributed web services and scraping pipelines.
- Own parts of the systems that gets data from web/mobile applications stores (GooglePlay, AppStore, Amazon).
- . Continuously work to improve the platforms monitoring, logging and alerting systems.
- Work closely with Reverse Engineers to understand APIs behaviors.
- Part of the DoD rotation to ensure services reliability 24/7.
- . Resolve escalated technical issues from production.
- . Help overhaul our existing infrastructure as we move to a microservices architecture.

Technologies: Python2.7/3.x, Bash, Scarpy, Celery, S3, PostgreSQL, Docker, Jenkins, ECS.

04/2019 - 10/2021 Nijmegen, NL

Software Engineer - Data Visualisation Censo

- . Work with an agile team to consistently deliver and maintain new features and functionalities
- . Understand the Energy field business and the business impact of the code.
- Ensured high quality data collection and maintaining the integrity of the data.
- . Communicate technical decisions through design docs, tech talks, and wikis.
- . Helping to improve our build processes to make deployment and iteration easier and faster.
- . Mentor junior engineers via pairing, design review, and code review.

Technologies: Python3, Django, GraphQl, Swagger, SonarCloud, PostgreSQL, JS, VueJS, Apollo.

06/2018 - 04/2019 Algiers, DZ

Software Engineer - Natural Language Processing Djezzy OTA

- Contribute in developing a platform for pre-processing and analyzing social media fans comments.
- Implement REST API which expose NLP model results.
- Participate in creating, testing and deploying Djezzy's mobile/web app.
- Documented all the workflow with design details and flowchart
- Provided extended support for Production releases and assisted in validating the releases.
- Responsible for code reviews, sprint planning and served as a scrum master.

Technologies: Python, Flask, Sentiment Analysis, NLP, Heroku, Data scraping.

02/2018 - 06/2018 Algiers, DZ

Graduated Data Scientist

Big-Mama

11/2017 - 06/2018

- Data Cleansing and preprocessing for different data science problems (Real Time Bidding).
- Implement Machine/Deep Learning Algorithms for Healthcare project.

Technologies: Python, TensorFlow, Pandas, Scala, Kafka, Akka Stream, MongoDB.

Intern, Master's Graduation Project

TALAA, Computer Science Dprt./USTHB

- Trained NLP ML models for Text Classification and an Algorithm for Automatic Text Summarization.
- . Created a recommendation system to suggest news articles to the users.
- Building Corpus for News Article classification (Ar/En).
- Developed a mobile app and REST api to expose and consume all previous modules.

Technologies: Python, ScikitLearn, Flask, AWS S3, React-Native, JavaScript, JSX, CSS3, MongoDB.

06/2017 - 11/2017 Algiers, DZ

Junior Web Developer

Hive-Digit

- Worked mainly on B2B e-Commerce platform and participate in the software architecture.
- Extensively write PHP backend code, unit testing and security audits.

Technologies: PHP, Yii2, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, REST API.

09/2015 - 06/2016 Algiers, DZ

Intern, Software Developer COSIDER Canalisations

- Updated an existing supply process information system.
- Developed an ERP module, integrated with Data visualization Dashboard.

Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, MySQL.

Interests

Open source contribution | Volunteer Work | Free/Open source software | Community Involvement | Club Memberships | Technical Books | Cooking

Skills & competences

Programming Language

Python 2.x/3.x, Bash Scripting

Frameworks, Libraries & Cloud

Django, Flask, Graphene, GraphQl, REST, AWS (API Gateway, ECS, EC2, Lambda)

Databases & Storage

RDBMS (PostgreSQL, MySQL), AWS (RDS, S3), Time Series DB: MongoDB, InfluxDB

Data Manipulation

Data Scraping, Data Cleansing, ETLs

Monitoring, Logging & Alerting

Grafana, AWS CloudWatch, Slack

Dev Tools

Git, Docker, AWS CLI, PagerDuty, Jenkins, SonarQube, Heroku

Education

09/2016 - 06/2018

Masters - Intelligent Computer Systems
University of Science and Technology, Algiers

Machine Learning | Natural Language Processing | Data Mining | Information Retrieval | Knowledge representation and reasoning | Constraint programming | e-Commerce & Web services | Advanced Databases.

09/2013 - 06/2016

Bachelor - Computer science

University of Science and Technology, Algiers

Mathematics | Algorithmics | Operational research | Computer architecture | Databases | Programming and Web development | Physics | Analog electronic.

Extracurricular

Algiers, DZ

02/2019 Colorado

HackCU Episode V Hackathon University of Colorado Boulder, USA

10/2018 Amsterdam

VEON Group
VEON Group

09/2018 Algiers

1st place winner Djezzy's Hackathon OTA Djezzy

05/2018 Abu Dhabi

1st place winner NYUAD Hackathon New York University

05/2016 - 08/2017 Algiers, Telemcen

CTF - Capture The Flag SIT CTF, Hack'tillS7our, MCTF

03/2017 Algiers

3rd place Hack!t National Hackathon Higher School of Computer Science

12/2016 Algiers

2nd place Algeria Web Awards Algiers department - AWA

05/2016 - 05/2018 Algiers

Git Trainer and GNU/Linux Install Party Organizer OpenMindsClub

Languages

Arabic(native) French(bilingue) English(advanced)